Guide to the Architectural Drawings and Maps of Yale University Buildings and Grounds
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Architectural drawings and maps of Yale University buildings and grounds
1723-2002
RU 1
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1782.67
(867 boxes)
The materials consist of design, preliminary, working, shop, and "as built" architectural drawings and maps of buildings and grounds owned or used by Yale University. The drawings range from original concepts to full scale details of equipment and ornamentation. The media vary from water colors, pen and ink sketches, pencil on tracing paper drawings to blueprints and photostats.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-A (YRG 46-A), Records and materials broadly documenting Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The drawings and maps included in this collection have come from a variety of sources, including transfers from the Yale offices concerned with building design, construction, and maintenance; other Yale offices; and individual donors. Additional drawings and maps of Yale buildings and facilities that do not form an integral body of records on their own are added to this collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Series I is available on aperture cards, and patrons must use the aperture cards instead of the original drawings. Special permission from the Head of Manuscripts and Archives is required to use original drawings in Series I.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Other Finding Aids
A spreadsheet (.xls) listing boxes and aperture cards by building is also available.
Existence and Location of Copies
Series I is available on aperture cards.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of design, preliminary, working, shop, and "as built" architectural drawings and maps of buildings and grounds owned or used by Yale University. The drawings range from original concepts to full scale details of equipment and ornamentation. The media vary from water colors, pen and ink sketches, pencil on tracing paper drawings to blueprints and photostats.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in two series: Series I. Drawings accessioned before 1980 and subsequently microfilmed. Series II. Drawings accessioned since 1980 and not microfilmed.
Appendix: Region List
1 Elm St > College St > Chapel St > High St (Old Campus block)
2 Chapel St > Howe St > George St > College St
3 Elm St > Howe St > Chapel St > York St
4 Elm St > York St > Chapel St > High St
5 Tower Parkway > Broadway > York St
6 Ashmun St > Lake Place > Dixwell Ave > Tower Parkway (Payne Whitney Gymnasium block)
7 Wall St > York St > Elm St > High St (Sterling Memorial Library/Trumbull College block)
8 Grove St > York St > Wall St > High St (Yale Law School block)
9 Wall St > High St > Elm St > College St (Cross Campus block)
10 Grove St > High St > Wall St > College St (Hewitt Quadrangle block)
11 Wall St > College St > Elm St > Church St
12 Grove St > College St > Wall St > Church St
13 Trumbull St > Prospect St > Grove St > Hillhouse Ave
14 Trumbull St > Hillhouse Ave > Grove St > Whitney Ave
15 Sachem St > Prospect St > Canal St
16 Sachem St > Prospect St > Trumbull St > Hillhouse Ave
17 Sachem St > Hillhouse Ave > Trumbull St > Whitney Ave
18 Edwards St > Whitney Ave > Trumbull St > Orange St
19 Highland St > Winchester Ave > Sachem St > Prospect
20 Edwards St > Prospect St > Sachem St > Whitney Ave
21 Canner St > Prospect St > Edwards St > Whitney Ave (Yale Divinity School)
22 South Frontage Rd > Park St > Howard Ave > Congress Ave (Yale-New Haven Medical Complex)
23 Observatories - excluding 135 Prospect and Winchester Observatory on Canner St
24 Outdoor Recreation Center and Yale forests - excluding Marsh Botanical Gardens and Marsh Hall
25 Athletic facilities - excluding boathouses and on-campus gymnasium
26 Boathouses and boats
27 Miscellaneous - not located in the on-campus regions
28 Yale-China campus (Chang-sha, Yuan-ling, Kwei-yang, Kwei-lin, Hsi-chow, Wu-chang, and Hong Kong)
90 Proposals for un-built structures, not including buildings subsequently constructed in a manner different from the original proposal, or proposed additions to buildings. (Proposals for constructed buildings can be located throughout the first 28 regions.)
92 Unidentified buildings
95 Maps of Yale properties
97 Non-Yale structures
98 Thesis drawings
Appendix: Region/Chronology List
1:1 Yale College House
1:2 Connecticut Hall (344 College St)
1:5 Brick Row
1:7 Second President's House [Analytical Lab] (380 College St, 1799-1860)
1:9 Conncecticut Lyceum (1803-1901)
1:10 Philosophical Building [1820 Commons; Cabinet] (1819-1890)
1:11 North College (Brick Row, 1820-1901)
1:14 Trumbull Gallery [Treasury Building]
1:16 Divinity College (Brick Row, 1835-1869)
1:17 Dwight Hall (67 High St, 1842/1846)
1:19 Alumni Hall (206 Elm)
1:20 Street Hall (1071 Chapel, 1864/1866)
1:23 Farnam Hall (380 College St)
1:24 Durfee Hall (198 Elm St, 1870/1871)
1:25 Battell Chapel
1:26 Pierson, Abraham statue (1874)
1:27 Silliman Statue
1:28 Dwight Hall (67 High St, 1885-1926)
1:30 Chittenden Hall (63 High St)
1:31 Osborn Hall (Corner of Chapel and College, 1888-1926)
1:32 Welch Hall (330 College St)
1:33 Vanderbilt Hall and Gateway (1035 Chapel St)
1:35 Phelps Hall and Gateway (344 College St)
1:36 Theodore Dwight Woolsey Statue
1:39 Linsly Hall (63 High St)
1:40 Wright Memorial Hall (206 Elm St, 1911/1912)
1:41 Daniels Memorial Gateway (202 Elm St)
1:44 Charles W. Bingham Hall (300 College St, 1926/1928)
2:1 1st President's House (Chapel St across from Yale College, 1722-1801)
2:2 Divinity House, Prof. of (York St, 1757/1758))
2:3 Medical School Building
2:8 Medical Laboratory (156 York St)
2:15 149 York Street
2:19 1094-1106 Chapel St (1966)
2:24 1074 Chapel St (1967)
2:25 1080 Chapel St (1967)
2:29 Yale Repertory Theatre (1120 Chapel St)
2:33 Yale Center for British Art (1080 Chapel St)
3:2 Yale University Club (184 York St)
3:3 Garland Apartments (242 York )
3:4 Wolf's Head (210 York )
3:6 226 York
3:7 University Theatre (222 York St)
3:25 Davenport College (248 York St)
3:25 Pierson College (231 Park St, 1930/1932)
3:26 Briton Hadden Memorial Building (202 York St)
3:32 Beta Theta Pi (204 York)
3:35 St. Thomas More Chapel and St. Thomas More House
3:36 245 York
3:37 Alpha Sigma Phi (217 Park St)
3:38 Manuscript (344 Elm St, 1956/1962)
3:43 Art and Architecture Building (182 York)
3:60 Zeta Psi (212 York)
3:61 Alumni House/Delta Kappa Epsilon (232 York)
3:63 Rose Alumni House [Delta Kappa Epsilon] (232 York St)
4:1 Skull and Bones (64 High St, 1856)
4:3 Peabody Museum (1873/76-1917)
4:4 Sloane Physical Laboratory (5 Library St, 1882/1883-1931)
4:28 Branford College (74 High St)
4:28 Saybrook College (242 Elm St)
4:28 Memorial Quadrangle
4:29 Weir Hall (66 High St)
4:31 199 York
4:34 Jonathan Edwards College (68 High St)
4:34 Jonathan Edwards College (Dickinson and Wheelock Halls)
4:37 Yale University Art Gallery (1111 Chapel St)
4:41 Library Street (1123-1125 Chapel St)
5:9 Alpha Chi Rho (310 York St)
5:10 Hall of Graduate Studies (320 York St)
5:14 27 Broadway
5:16 Morse College (302 York St)
5:17 Ezra Stiles College (19 Tower Pkwy)
5:18 Old Yale Coop (77 Broadway, 1962)
6:4 Central Power Plant (18 Ashmun, 1918)
6:5 University Operations
6:10 74 Ashmun
6:16 Payne Whitney Gymnasium (70 Tower Pkwy)
6:17 Thompkins, Ray House (20 Tower Pkwy, 1931/1932)
6:25 32 Ashmun
6:26 30 Ashmun
6:28 50-52 Ashmun
6:29 56 Ashmun
6:33 34-44 Ashmun
7:4 University Gymnasium (Sloan Gym, 1890/92-1932)
7:5 Carnegie Swimming Pool
7:10 Psi Upsilon (120 High)
7:25 Artillery Hall (1917-1927)
7:30 Zeta Psi (301 York St, 1898/1899
7:31 Sterling Memorial Library (120 High St)
7:35 245-247 Elm
7:36 Trumbull College (241 Elm St)
8:1 Hopkins Hall (134 High St, 1840-1930)
8:16 Sterling Law Buildings (127 Wall St)
9:2 East Divinity Hall [Edwards Hall] (1869/1870-1931)
9:4 West Divinity Hall (Taylor)
9:14 Gibbs Hall (125 High St, 1895-1932)
9:15 Music School [President's House] (470 College St, 1886-1919)
9:16 Fayerweather Hall (1900/01-1933)
9:20 Haughton Hall (1909-1933)
9:21 Day Missions Library (1911-1931)
9:23 Porter Gateway (1902)
9:24 Albert Sprague Memorial Hall (470 College St, 1916/1917)
9:26 120 College
9:33 William L. Harkness Hall (100 Wall St)
9:34 Calhoun College (189 Elm St)
9:35 Berkeley College (205 Elm St)
9:36 Cross Campus Library (120 High St)
10:1 Scroll and Key (490 College St, 1869)
10:13 University Dining Hall (Commons) (168 Grove St)
10:13 Woolsey Hall (College and Grove, 1900/1901)
10:18 Woodbridge Hall (105 Wall St)
10:24 Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library (123 Wall St, 1963)
10: Allen Keith Memorial
10: Plan of Hewitt Quadrangle with Bicentennial Buildings
10: Proposed Administration Building
11:3 Hendrie Hall (165 Elm St)
11:6 Elizabethan Club (459 College St)
11:7 76 Wall
11:10 66 Wall
11:17 Dept. of Health [School of Music] (435 College St, 1930)
11:18 325-27 Temple
11:19 Stoeckel Hall (96 Wall St)
12:1 Saint Anthony Hall, Old [Delta Psi] (483 College, 1894-1913)
12:7 Byers Hall (505 College St)
12:8 Vanderbilt-Scientific Halls (#1) (77-87 Wall St, 1903/06)
12:11 Vanderbilt-Scientific Halls (#2) (505 College St, 1906)
12:21 Bureau of Appointments Building (144 Grove St)
12:26 Timothy Dwight College (345 Temple St)
12:28 Silliman College (505 College St)
12:29 St. Anthony Hall (493 College St)
13:1 South Sheffield Hall (159 Grove St)
13:2 North Sheffield Hall (45 Prospect, 1872-1967)
13:3 Sheffield Mansion (6 Hillhouse Ave)
13:5 Winchester Hall (15 Prospect St, 1842-1968)
13:16 Sheffield-Sterling-Strathcona Hall (1931/1932)
13:17 Dana House (24 Hillhouse Ave)
13:18 Becton Engineering and Applied Science Center (15 Prospect St)
14:4 Mason Laboratory (9 Hillhouse Ave, 1911)
14:11 Warner House [Book and Snake] [The Cloister] (1 Hillhouse)
14:15 Vernon Hall (370 Temple)
14:16 430 Temple (1956)
14:22 Rosenfeld Hall (Saint Elmo Hall)
14:25 University Health Services Center (17 Hillhouse, 1971)
14:31 88 Trumbull
15:1 Old Sigma Kappa (124 Prospect, 1890-1906)
15:2 Hammond Hall (14 Mansfield St)
15:6 Book and Bond (8 Prospect St, 1899)
15:9 Social Science Library [Berkeley Divinity; Urban Hall] (140 Prospect Street, 1957)
16:6 89 Trumbull
16:7 87 Trumbull
16:8 111 Prospect (38 Hillhouse)
16:10 135 Prospect Street
16:11 60 Sachem
17:0 Survey of Hillhouse Property
17:5 John North House (158 Whitney)
17:9 President's House (43 Hillhouse Ave)
17:12 85 Trumbull
18:4 155 Whitney
19:2 Marsh Hall [Marsh House, 1878] (360 Prospect St)
19:7 Irving Fisher House (460 Prospect)
19:17 David S. Ingalls Rink (73 Sachem St)
19:19 William B. Greeley Memorial Lab (370 Prospect, 1959)
19:25 218 Prospect
20:1 Sloane Physics Laboratory (217 Prospect, 1911/1912)
20:2 Osborn Memorial Laboratory (165 Prospect St)
20:3 Pierson-Sage Power Plant (41 Sachem, 1913)
20:5 Sterling Chemistry Laboratory (225 Prospect St)
20:6 Peabody Museum of Natural History (170 Whitney Ave)
20:7 Sage-Bowers Hall (205 Prospect St)
20:11 Sachem's Wood (1828)
20:13 Accelerator Laboratories (272 Whitney Ave)
20:14 Josiah Williard Gibbs Research Laboratories (260 Whitney Ave, 1955)
20:15 Peabody Museum (Oceanography and Ornithology Lab - West Wing of Peabody Museum)
20:19 Kline Geology Laboratory (210 Whitney Ave)
20:21 Arthur Wright Nuclear Structures Laboratory (272 Whitney Ave, 1964)
20:23 Kline Biology Tower (219 Prospect St)
21:1 Winchester Observatory
21:4 Heliostat Building (Canner St, 1915-1957)
21:6 Sterling Divinity Quadrangle (409 Prospect St)
21:9 Bellamy Hall (Canner, 1957)
22:1 North Ward [State Hospital; Knight Hospital] (1833-1930)
22:7 George Bronson Farnam Operating Ampitheatre
22:14 Medical Clinic Amphitheatre
22:22 Jane Ellen Hope Memorial Building (315 Cedar St)
22:24 Howard Building [Isolation Pavillion] (Howard and Davenport, 1914-1963)
22:29 Nathan Smith Hall (62 Park)
22:46 Private Pavilion (Winchester Hospital)
22:50 Sterling Hall of Medicine (333 Cedar St)
22:50 Sterling Hall of Medicine, Library Wing (333 Cedar St)
22:51 Sterling Power Plant (309 Congress Ave)
22:61 Brady Laboratory Annex (310 Cedar St)
22:67 Farnam Memorial Building (310 Cedar St)
22:68 Lauder Hall (310 Cedar St)
22:99 Raleigh Fitkin Memorial Pavilion (789 Howard, 1928/1930)
22:134 Tompkins, Sarah Wey memorial Pavillion (789 Howard St, 1931/1932)
22:145 Laundry (Yale-New Haven Hospital)
22:165 Connecticut Mental Health Center (34 Park St)
22:167 Laboratory of Epidemiology and Public Health
22:168 Laboratory of Clinical Investigation (Howard and Davenport, 1965)
22:188 Betsy Ross House ( 1 South St)
23:3 Bethany Observing Station (Bethany, CT, 1958)
23:4 Yale-Columbia Observatory (Southern Observatory)
25:1 Yale Field (251-257 Derby Ave, West Haven, 1902)
25:2 Yale Bowl (251 Derby Ave, West Haven, 1902)
25:3 Yale Armory (70 Central Ave, 1917)
25:4 Yale Golf Course (102 Ray Rd, 1923)
25:5 Lapham Field House (355 Derby Ave, West Haven, 1924)
25:6 Walter Camp Field Gateway (251 Derby Ave, 1927/1928)
25:9 Quonset Huts (Quarters for Veterans, circa 1945))
26:1 Tomlinson's Bridge Boat House (Quinnipiac River, New Haven Harbor, 1866-1875)
26:2 Yale Boat House (258 East Chapel, 1875-1910)
26:3 Gales Ferry Boat House (Gales Ferry, CT)
26:4 Adee Boat House (74 Forbes Ave, East Haven, 1909/1910)
26:5 Bob Cook Boat House (Housatonic River, Housatonic Ave, Derby, CT, 1924)
27:6 Liggett Building [Exchange Building] (855-871 Chapel St, 1928)
27:12 Amity Animal Research Facility [Yale Amity Farm] (Old Amity Rd, Bethany, CT, 1960)
27:20 Armory (192 Armory)
27:24 Lewis Walpole Library (Farmington, CT, 1980)
27:25 W. S. Lewis House (Walpole Library)
27:28 Yale Farms
28:2 Atterbury Memorial Chapel (Yali) (Changsha, China, 1916-1942)
28:11 Wright Dormitory (Yali) (Changsha, China)
28:15 Chang Sha Hunan in China
28:15 Hsiang-Ya Hospital (Changsha, China)
28:35 Anatomy Building (Hsiang-Ya)
28:64 Animal House (Hsiang-Ya)
28:76 University Health Center (New Asia College)
90:10 Dormitory Region 1
90:20 Gateway Region 1
90:23 University Development Region 1
90:25 Hillhouse Property Development
90:27 Berkeley Oval Dorm Extension
90:29 Library for Yale-China
90:30 Theatre (unidentified region)
90:31 Proposed Medical School Development
90:35 Proposed Dormitory (High, York, Elm, Library Streets)
90:40 Tunnel across College Street
90:50 Ice Skating Rink (unidentified location)
90:53 Proposed University Development
90:60 Dormitory Region 1
90:70 Dormitory Region 1
90:80 Yale Memorial Receiving Vault (Mausoleum)
90:83 Medical School Development
90:90 Ward Unit "A" Region 22
90:100 Ward Unit "A" Region 22
90:100 Women's Dormitory
90:100 Women's Dormitory (unidentified region)
90:104 Library Building (Central China College)
90:105 Chemistry Laboratory (Central China College)
90:106 Procter Memorial Building (Central China College--Wuchang)
90:107 Physics Laboratory (Central China College--Wuchang)
90:110 Chemical Engineering Laboratory
90:117 3 Barracks Buildings (Region 20)
90:120 Yale-China Reconstruction
90:122 Administration Building (corner of Wall and High)
90:128 Dormitory
90:130 New Campus
90:140 Berkeley Divinity School Housing (Region 15)
90:150 High-Wall Complex (Region 10)
90:160 Berkeley Divinity School Housing (Region 15)
90:170 Berkeley Divinity School Development
90:185 Whitney Avenue
92:1 Alteration for a library and photography area
92:2 Fire-proof exhibit room and book vault
92:3 Sketch of partial plan
92:4 Elevation and plan of new gate
92:6 Elevation and plan of stairway
92:8 Front stoop (alterations)
92:10 Sketch of interior common room
92:11 Sketch of museum case and museum floor plan
92:12 Music Room (?)
92:13 Typical floor plan 1971
92:15 FSD of granite head, jamb, and sill of basement windows
92:16 Telephone switching and booth
92:18 Lettering
92:19 Details of stoop gate 1901
92:20 Interior elevations
95:5 Land in Plainfield
95:6 Land between Howe, Dwight, Elm, and Whalley
95:7 Lot between Temple and Church
95:8 Land from Howe to Dwight and beyond
95:9 Plan of land at north end of Plainfield (Stephen Bull's land)
95:10 Lots of land laid out by Moses Marsfield, heirs of Theophilus Eaton, Thomas Leek, etc.
95:20 Tract sold by Col. Ball to W. C. Whitney
95:22 Lots on Howe, Sherman, Martin, Samaritin
95:26 Farm in Oxford, CT bequeathed by Sheldon Park
95:27 Red Oak Farm in Oxford, CT, bequeated by Sheldon Park
95:28 Land in Oxford, CT, bequeathed by Sheldon Park
95:30 Building lots on Dwight and Martin Streets
95:34 Building lots on Gill Street
95:40 Map of the "President's pasture" on Maple, Howe, Whalley, Dwight
95:44 Diagram of Yale land with extension of Dwight Street from Maple to Whalley laid out by Wyllis Warner
95:50 Proposed street on Whalley, Dwight, and Maple block
95:60 Land from Whitney to Rock St., Mill River, Orange, and Cold Spring
95:70 Hillhouse, Grove, Prospect, Trumbull Streets
95:75 Old Campus--sewer, water and gas lines
95:80 Old Campus plus Library Street--heating and water
95:85 College buildings west of High Street--Sloane Lab, Kent Lab, Commons (old)
95:86 Elm Street--Peabody Museum (old) and Old Gymnasium
95:87 Old Campus plus Psychological Lab and Divinity (old)
95:95 Wall, College, Grove, High Streets, Scroll and Key
95:98 Cedar, Congress, Rose Streets
95:100 College, Chapel, York Streets to Wall Street
95:104 Old Campus--Bicentennial torchlight procession
95:106 Chapel, York, Grove, Prospect, Trumbull, and Elm Streets to College
95:111 Corner of Park and Edgewood Streets
95:115 Chapel, York, Broadway, York Sq. Pl., Ashmun, canal, Sachem, Mansfield, Whitney, Elm, College
95:121 Rose Street block: property lines on half, buildings on half
95:122 Congress, Howard, Davenport, Broad, Palmer, Rose Streets
95:123 Chapel, York, Grove, College Streets
95:124 120, 122, 126 College Street
95:125 Winchester and Sachem Streets
95:130 Old Campus--sidewalks
95:132 Chapel, York, Grove, and College Streets
95:133 NW corner of Elm and High
95:136 York and Ashmun Streets
95:140 York, High, Elm, and Library (Herrick Hall, Carpenter shop, store house, heating plant)
95:141 York, Elm, High, Library Streets (heating plant)
95:145 Crown, York, Boradway, York Sq. Pl., Ashmun, Bristol, canal, Webster, Sachem, Whitney, Church, etc.
95:146 Sachem, Winchester, Woodland, Mansfield, Division, Prospect, Highland, Whitney
95:148 Pierson-Sage Square: Prospect, Edwards, Whitney Streets to Sachem
95:150 Chapel, York, Grove, College: plot plan of tunnels and electrical conduits
95:152 Chapel, York, Library, High Streets
95:156 Plot plan of tunnels: Chapel, York, Grove, College Streets
95:162 Congress, Howard, Davenport, Broad, Palmer, Rose Streets
95:170 Cedar, Broad, Rose, Congress Streets
95:180 Pierson-Sage Square
95:186 Map of Property.218-226 York Steet
95:192 Elm, College, Wall, High Streets
95:202 NW corner of College and Chapel Streets
95:205 Congress, Howard, Davenport, Broad, Palmer, and Rose Streets
95:210 Wall, York, Grove, High Streets
95:213 York, Ashmun, York Square Place
95:215 Grove, York Square Place, Ashmun, Lake Place, Dixwell
95:230 Broad, Cedar, Davenport Streets
95:233 South, York, Oak, Davenport Streets
95:236 College, Grove, High, Wall Streets
95:238 Cedar, Congress, Howard, Davenport
95:240 Elm, College, Wall, Temple Streets
95:243 College, Chapel, High, Elm Streets
95:248 Plan for dev'l.: Chapel, York, Ashmun, Lock, Canal, Prospect, Trumbull, Temple, Elm, College
95:252 Elm, College, Wall, High Streets
95:257 Palmer, Rose, Lafayette, and Broad Streets
95:262 Chapel, York, Library, High Streets
95:263 Chapel, York, Library, High Streets
95:267 York, Chapel, Park, Elm
95:269 168, 178 Prospect and 61 Mansfield: Mansfield, Sachem, Prospect Streets
95:272 Pierson-Sage Square
95:277 Elm, College, Wall, High Streets
95:282 Elm, College, Wall, High Streets
95:290 Elm, College, Wall, High Streets
95:292 Elm, College, Wall, High Streets
95:314 Campus
95:315 Campus with President's House, no Timothy Dwight, Berkeley, Calhoun Colleges
95:316 Campus with Timothy Dwight College, Berkeley College, and President's House
95:325 Chapel, Park, Broadway, Lake Place, canal, Prospect Pl., Prospect, Trumbull, Whitney, Church Streets
95:326 Edwards, Prospect, Highland, Livingston Streets
95:346 Insurance map of Campus
95:358 Bethany, CT properties
95:376 Insurance map of Campus
95:386 Insurance map of Campus
95:392 Campus
95:420 Broadway, Ashmun, Grove St. Cemetery, Trumbull, Temple, Wall, York Streets--plumbing
97:1 Roy D. Chapin (non-Yale)
97:2 Simeon E. Baldwin house at 44 Wall Street (non-Yale)
97:3 Tapping Reeve House, Litchfield, CT (non-Yale)
98:1 Thesis project of Victor M. Reynal: Library
98:2 Thesis project of Porter McCray: Addition to Art Gallery
Campus planning; College buildings -- Design and construction; Universities and colleges -- Landscape architecture; Architectural drawings (visual works); Architectural records; Maps (documents); Yale College (1718-1887) -- Buildings; Yale University -- Buildings
- Yale Architectural drawings and maps (microfilmed), circa 1880-1980; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series I is available on aperture cards. Patrons must use this format. Special permission from the Head of Manuscripts and Archives is required to use original drawings in Series I.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains architectural drawings which were accessioned prior to 1980. These drawings were microfilmed as part of the Yale Architectural Archives Project. Information about the drawing (e.g., building, job, drawing set, documentation type, date, architect) was coded and entered into a database. Aperture cards containing the coded information along with a negative image of the drawing are available in Manuscripts and Archives. The database was used to produce printed indexes to the drawings by building, architect, date of drawing, and image number.
  Arranged by region/chronology code. See Appendix for full listing of buildings arranged by region/chronology.
  A spreadsheet (.xls) listing boxes and aperture cards by building is also available.
  - 1:01 Yale College (Box 1)
  - 1:02 Connecticut Hall (Folder 2)
  - 1:05 Old Brick Row
    - Elevations and plans of present and projected buildings of Yale College by John Trumbull (original and photstat), 1793 (Folder 3)
      Left to right, buildings identified by Trumbull as "Projected Building, Chapel, Present Building, Buildings which may be erected hereafter." Illustrates the beginnings of the Old Brick Row.
    - John Trumbull's Brick Row planting plan around The Temples of Cloacina (original and photostats), 1793 (Folder 3)
  - 1:07 Second President's House (Folder 4)
  - 1:09 Connecticut Lyceum (Folder 5)
  - 1:10 Philosophical Building (Folder 6)
  - 1:14 Trumbull Gallery (Folder 7)
  - 1:16 Divinity College (Folder 8)
  - 1:17 Dwight Hall (67 High St) (Folder 9)
  - 1:19 Alumni Hall (206 Elm) (Folder 10)
  - 1:20 Street Hall (Folder 11)
  - 1:23 Farnam Hall (380 College St) (Folder 12)
  - 1:24 Durfee Hall (198 Elm St) (Folder 13)
  - 1:25 Battell Chapel (Folder 14)
  - 1:30 Chittenden Hall (63 High St) (Folder 15)
  - 1:31 Osborn Hall (Folder 16)
  - 1:32 Welch Hall (330 College St) (Folder 17)
  - 1:33 Vanderbilt Hall (1035 Chapel St) (Folder 18)
  - 1:35 Phelps Archway (Folder 19)
  - 1:35 Phelps Archway (Folder 20)
  - 1:39 Linsly Hall (63 High St) (Folder 21)
  - 1:41 Daniels Memorial Gateway (202 Elm St) (Folder 22)
  - 1:44 Charles W. Bingham Hall (300 College St) (Box 23)
  - 2:01 First President's House (Folder 24)
  - 2:03 (York Street) Medical School (Folder 25)
  - 2:33 British Art Center
    - first project - preliminary drawings (Box 26A)